JEYA PRAKASH S

WEB DEVELOPER AND UI/UX DESIGNER

Contact: +91-9976605533

E-mail id: jeyaprakashs04@gmail.com

Linked In: <u>Jeya Prakash S</u>



Jeya Prakash | Portfolio

ABOUT ME

A Computer Science and Engineering Student pursuing my degree in Annamalai University with proficient in a variety of programming languages and design tools, with a strong focus on user-centered design principles. A highly skilled and motivated Front End Developer and UI/UX Designer, building and maintaining websites and designing engaging user experiences.

EDUCATION

• Annamalai University 2020 - 2024

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering 8.76/10 GPA

• Star Matriculation Higher Secondary School

HSC (2019-2020) SSLC (2017-2018) ary Scho

83%

SKILLS

- Web Development
- C / C++ Programming
- Python Programming
- SQL Programming
- UI/UX Designing
- Graphic Designing

TOOLS

- · Git and GitHub
- VS Code
- Eclipse IDE

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Vice President

The Institution of Engineers - Annamalai University

Class Representative

Annamalai University (2020 to 2023)

CERTIFICATIONS

- C Programming
- Python Programming
- Meta's Frontend Development
- Web Development
- UI/UX Designing

EXPERIENCE

- Web Development and CRM Intern (Onsite)
 Bharat Natural Elements (June 2023 to July 2023)
- Web Development and Designing Internship
 Oasis Infobyte (Jan 2023 to Feb 2023)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- MS Office
- Video Editing
- Digital Marketing
- Effective Team Collaborator
- Professional Leadership

PROJECTS

'JESI'- The Virtual Voice Assistant using python

Voice assistants are software agents that can interpret human speech and respond via synthesized voices. In this project I use the method, Speech recognition is the process of converting audio into text. This is commonly used in voice assistants like Alexa, Siri, etc.

Temperature Converter Website - HTML/CSS, JavaScript

This Website helps convert the temperature between Fahrenheit and Celsius scale.